woodcraft.com 2015-06-23

# Woodcraft's Privacy Policy

Our commitment to privacy 

Your privacy is important to us. Woodcraft is a long time member of The DMA (Direct Marketing Association) and supports their Privacy Promise Program. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available at the bottom of every single page on the website. 

What information do we collect? How do we use it? 

When you order, we need to know your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, credit-card number and expiration date. This allows us to process and fulfill your orders, and notify you of your order status. Your phone number is necessary for UPS and International shipping. It will also be used to contact you if there is a question regarding your order. Phone numbers will not be used for sales calls. Our secure traffic is encrypted using the TLS protocol with a 1024 bit Public Key Certificate. 

We occasionally make our customer list (postal mailing list only) available to carefully screened companies whose products may interest you. If you do not wish to receive their mailings, we will be sure your name is removed from the list we share with other organizations. Please contact us at the address listed below and provide us with your exact name and address. 

Woodcraft Supply, LLC  
PO Box 1686  
Parkersburg, WV 26102, USA  
1-800-535-4482 

Or send us an email at [custserv@woodcraft.com](mailto:custserv@woodcraft.com)

If you supply us with your postal address online you may receive periodic mailings from us with information on new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such mailings from Woodcraft, please contact us at the address listed above. 

You may voluntarily sign up to receive our Woodcraft Email to learn more about special offers. For this service we need an e-mail address and zip code which we use to send the information you requested. E-mail addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties. 

When you enter a contest or other promotional feature, we may ask for your name, address, phone number and e-mail address, so we can administer the contest and notify winners. 

We personalize your shopping experience by using your purchases to shape our recommendations about other merchandise that might be of interest to you. We also monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage to help us develop the design and layout of the store. 

The information collected by our website may include: Any details you enter and submit, such as name, address, email address, etc. Your IP address, referrer, web pages you visit and other data normally stored in website logs. Session information stored in cookies that are used to ensure accurate data is extracted from our systems. These cookies do not include any personal data. Under no circumstances will we hold sensitive payment details such as your credit card number, expiry date and security code.

Any information we collect will be used in accordance with applicable laws for the following purposes: To comply with legal requirements. In certain cases, we may use your email address to send you information about products, services, or in support of a transaction – completed or otherwise. In such a case, you will be offered the option to opt in/out. We may use personal information for auditing, research and analysis to operate and improve our technologies and services.

How do we protect customer information? 

Personal information is collected when an account is set up for a purchase transaction using SSL encryption. Only that information which is needed to complete the transaction is required. Your account is password protected, and you can access it at anytime. 

Woodcraft maintains a strict "no-spam" policy. Your e-mail address will never be sold to a third party. We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems. We restrict access to personal information to Woodcraft employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. 

What about "cookies"? 

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information, but they do enable us to provide features such as storring your items in your shopping cart between visits. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent that. Even without a cookie, you can still use most of the features in our store, including placing items in your shopping cart and purchasing them.

Woodcraft participates in display advertising, display network impression reporting and remarketing efforts on Google. As a result, Woodcraft permits: 

> Third party vendors, including Google, to show our ads on sites on the internet.  
>  Third party vendors, including Google, to use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to your website.  
>  Third party vendors, including Google, to use first and third-party cookies to report how age, gender and interests as well as ad impressions, other uses of ad services and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to your website   
>  You may opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/).  
> 

I don't like the Woodcraft ads that show on non-Woodcraft sites. How do I stop the ads? 

1\. To "opt-out" of display ads, click on the triangle in the top right corner of any ad. 

2\. This will take you to the "About Google Ads" page:

3\. Scroll down the page until you see "How you can manage your ads settings", then click on "Ads Settings"

4\. Next click on the Opt out setting that works for you

You can also click 

[Google Ad Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) to read more about how to manage these settings. 

Our commitment to children's privacy 

Woodcraft's web site contains no objectionable material and is considered to be "child safe." Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information on our website from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13. 

In summary

We are committed to protecting your privacy. We use the information we collect on the site to make shopping at Woodcraft possible and to enhance your overall shopping experience. 

Your consent 

By using our web site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by Woodcraft. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

Tell us what you think 

Woodcraft welcomes your questions and comments about privacy. Please e-mail us at [custserv@woodcraft.com](mailto:custserv@woodcraft.com)
